What? Friends?
什麼？朋友？
You mean close friends?
妳是說好朋友嗎？
About three, I think.
大概三個吧
Hold on a second.
等一下
Hey, kid.
嘿，孩子
-Who is it? -Mom.
-是誰？ -媽媽
Hurry up! It's an international call.
快點，是國際電話
Four, I guess. One of them, I'm not sure about.
四個吧，其中一個我不確定
Shuji.
哥哥
-Me? -It's Mom. Hurry up!
-我？ -是媽媽，快點
-Yes? -How many friends do you have?
-什麼事？ -你有幾個朋友？
I've never really counted.
我沒有認真算過
-You don't have friends? -Yes, I do!
-你沒有朋友嗎？ -我有啊
Then how many?
那有幾個？
What?
什麼？
-Hurry up! Time's running out! -Fine! Two!
-快點，快沒時間了 -好吧，兩個
What was that all about?
這通電話是怎麼回事？
So you've got two friends?
你有兩個朋友？
Oh, is that funny guy who stayed here one of them?
那個住在這裡的搞笑男 是其中一個嗎？
That guy who's a karate expert.
那個空手道高手
Yip!
嗷
No, not him.
不，不是他
And who's the other?
另一個是誰？
I know! That girl!
我知道，是那個女孩
-Oh, the keychain girl? -Yes!
-那個鑰匙圈女孩？ -對啊
Nobuta power charge!
野豬能量，注入
-Nobuta!
-野豬
Is Nobuta your friend, Shuji?
野豬是哥哥的朋友嗎？
Don't you call her Nobuta.
你別叫她野豬啦
She's your friend, right?
她是你的朋友，對吧？
Being hated…
被其他人討厭
by others...
那種感覺
sure is terrifying.
真的很可怕
It's okay.
沒關係
Nobody will hate you.
沒有人會討厭你
Is she?
是嗎？
-What? -Is she?
-什麼？ -是嗎？
Go to bed!
去睡覺啦
Hurry up!
快點
Fine.
好啦
Ever since that day,
從那天起
Nobuta has been avoiding me.
野豬一直在躲我
Nobuta…
野豬
I know this can't last forever though.
我知道不能一直這樣下去
I guess,
我想…
my only choice is to talk to her in the classroom.
唯一的選擇就是去教室找她談
Holy crap.
糟糕
Everyone's watching.
大家都在看
Well…
那個…
Wait! I need your help with something! Catherine needs some help.
等等，我需要妳幫忙 凱瑟琳需要幫忙
Morning four meters!
早安，四公尺
There it is! A new record!
-來了，新紀錄
Catherine needs some help.
凱瑟琳需要幫忙
I'll start being your producer again, Nobuta.
我想繼續野豬改造計畫
That's all I wanted to tell you.
我想說的就是這個
I'm through with being produced for.
我不想再被改造了
What? Why?
什麼？為什麼？
Well… I mean… After what I did…
因為…我做了那件事
Wasn't that…
那不是…
I mean…
我是說…
You were
妳當時…
just trying to cheer me up, right?
只是想安慰我，對吧？
Right. Then… Well… Thank you.
對吧，那麼我要謝謝妳
That's the end of that, okay?
那就別再想那件事了，好嗎？
Aren't you angry?
你不生氣嗎？
Why would I be?
我為什麼要生氣？
Well… I mean… What I did
因為…我做的事
was so thoughtless.
太隨便了
No, not at all. I'm to blame as well.
不，沒這回事，我也有不對的地方
To be honest, I didn't know how to react.
老實說，我不知道該如何反應
I'm not a person who gets cheered up so much.
我不太常接受別人的安慰
What about Mariko?
真理子呢？
Do you think anyone was there to cheer her up that day?
你覺得那天有人安慰她嗎？
Nobody likes to be alone, do they?
沒有人喜歡孤單，對吧？
I guess you're right.
說得也是
You know better than anyone what it's like to be alone.
妳比任何人都清楚孤單的滋味
If possible, I want every single person to find happiness.
可以的話 我希望每個人都能獲得幸福
Well… I don't think that's possible.
那是不可能的吧
The three of us
我們三個人
started getting together again.
又開始聚在一起了
Wait. Don't tell me you made that.
等等，這該不會是你做的吧
-Yes. -Wow!
-是啊 -真厲害
Okay, the three of us will pull it together.
我們三個人一起拉吧
Ready. Nobuta!
一、野豬
Sorry.
抱歉
Ready. Go!
一、二
When I look back on it,
現在回想起來
the party ball was just like my future.
那顆彩球就像我的未來
Nobody could stop me from falling.
誰都無法阻止我墜落
NOBUTA PRODUCTION RESTART
（重啟野豬改造計畫）
-Oh, dear. -That doesn't bode well.
-天啊 -真不是好兆頭
Hey.
嘿
-Make another one. -Yes.
-再做一個吧 -對啊
Make one.
做一個啊
-You make it.
-那你做啊 -你來做
Let's Rochambeau for it.
猜拳決定
Ready, set, good!
剪刀、石頭、布
There was nothing I could do…
我自己什麼都做不了
and I just fell.
只能一直往下墜
Ready, set, good!
剪刀、石頭、布
-Let go of me! -Come on, talk with me for a while.
-放開我 -來嘛，跟我聊一下
Let go! I told you to cut it out!
放手，我不是叫你住手嗎？
-What the hell did you do that for? -Don't get violent!
-妳幹嘛這樣？ -不要使用暴力
-Fuck off, prick! -Why don't you fuck off?
-滾開，混蛋 -怎麼不是你滾開？
Now, now! Don't get violent!
好了，不要使用暴力
Get the fuck out of my way!
給我滾開
You fucking prick!
你這混帳
-I told you, don't get violent! -You fucking prick! Fuck off!
-不要使用暴力 -你這混帳，滾開
Hey, you there!
喂，你們在做什麼？
-What the hell are you doing? -That man and a woman were fighting!
-你到底在做什麼？ -那男人在和女人吵架
-What woman? -Some office worker.
-什麼女人？ -某位上班族
-What office worker? -I'm not involved!
-什麼上班族？ -不關我的事
-Come with me. -But I'm not involved!
-跟我來 -但這跟我沒有關係
-Tell your story later. -I'm not involved!
-等等再說 -不關我的事
I didn't hit anyone.
我沒有打任何人
-Please, believe me. -Everyone says that.
-請相信我 -大家都這麼說
-"Please, believe me." -But I didn't…
-“請相信我” -但我沒有…
-I was just passing by. -I told you.
-我只是路過而已 -我不是說了嗎？
That's what they all say.
大家都會這麼說
-Kon-chan. -Yes? Oh, hi there.
-小近 -是？你來啦
Hold on a second.
等一下
-Wait. -You sit tight for a minute.
-等等 -你先別亂跑啊
Coming.
來了
Oh, well, well! What's this?
哎呀…怎麼啦？
It's over.
結束了
My life is totally over.
我的人生徹底毀了
Hey, son.
嘿，孩子
I'm the chairman of the neighborhood council.
我是自治會的會長
In this world, the truth doesn't matter.
在這個世界上，真相並不重要
What matters is if you're a man who can be believed or not.
重要的是你是否是個值得信任的男人
What's more, son,
還有，孩子
even if you're devastated, it doesn't mean life is over!
就算是遍體鱗傷 人生也不會就此結束
Life continues after a disaster!
人生經歷大難，還是得繼續啊
Life doesn't end that easily!
人生不會那麼簡單就結束了
All right?
懂嗎？
DELIVERY SEASON
（外送季）
Oh, my brother!
大哥
It's great to see you again! It's me, Hiroshi!
很高興再見到你，是我啊，阿浩
I haven't seen you in so long!
好久不見
-I brought this for you. -Thank you very much!
-我帶了這個給你 -非常感謝
It's really frightening when nobody believes you.
沒人相信你時，真的好可怕
Thankfully, there was a witness.
幸好當時有目擊者
But if there hadn't been one,
如果沒有的話
I would still be there.
我現在還會待在那裡
As long as you have life, there will be miserable days.
只要活著，就會有悲慘的日子
However,
但是…
there will also be awesome days.
也會有很棒的日子
That's life!
這就是人生
IDEAS WANTED FOR LUNCHTIME BROADCAST
（午間廣播招募企劃案）
What's that? Did you get into a fight?
那是什麼？你跟人打架了嗎？
-Can I rip it off? -Leave me be!
-可以撕下來嗎？ -少煩我
-Rip! -Cut it out!
-我撕 -住手
-Why rip it off? -Rip!
-為什麼要撕掉？ -我撕
Oh, your idea is for a live broadcast.
妳想要做直播的企劃啊
If this is selected, you'll be the reporter, Nobuta?
如果這個入選的話 妳就是播報員嗎？
Wow!
天啊
-Yes. -Seriously?
-對 -真的嗎？
-Wow! -This is a great chance!
-天啊 -這是個好機會
Hey, you! Help us think of something.
喂，幫我們想想辦法吧
I'm not a member of the broadcast club anymore.
我現在已經不是廣播社的人了
So? You can think.
所以呢？你有腦子吧
Quit laughing.
別笑了
There must be something. Come here, Nobuta.
一定有什麼方法，過來，野豬
If this idea is accepted,
如果這個企劃被採納
Nobuta will become the noontime face of Sumidagawa High.
野豬將成為隅田川高中的午間門面了
Whoa! The Mr. Mino of Sumidagawa High!
隅田川高中的三野先生
-Her? -I think you mean Mr. Tamori.
-就是她 -你是想說塔摩利先生吧
-Careless mistake. -"Careless mistake"?
-口誤 -“口誤”？
Hold this.
妳拿著這個
Not like Mr. Mino. How about this? Yonesuke!
不要用三野先生的風格 這樣如何？桂米助風
Nice!
很好啊
Hello.
大家好
It's time for "Attack! Kotani's Surprise Lunch Check."
現在是“小谷的午餐突襲”時間
For the first episode, I'll be surprise checking Mr. Yokoyama's lunch.
第一集我會突擊檢查橫山老師的便當
Well…
那個…
Not today! Today's is really bad! Don't do this today!
今天不行，今天真是不行 不要今天拍
Excuse me.
不好意思
I LOVE YOU
（我愛你）
Who made this?
這是誰做的？
I made this myself.
是我自己做的
It's good, isn't it?
好吃吧？
Yuck.
難吃
How dare you say "yuck"?
妳說難吃是什麼意思？
-You're back! -Hello.
-妳來啦 -你好
-May I have some? -Sure. Go right ahead.
-我可以吃一點嗎？ -好啊，吃吧
Yuck.
難吃
There it is! Kotani's "yuck!"
出現了，小谷的招牌“難吃”
-You can tell by her face how awful it is! -Yes!
-看她的表情就知道有多難吃 -對啊
THIS IS SOYMILK
（這是豆子乳）
Yuck.
難吃
Hey!
喂
-Your "yuck" is really funny. -No, it's not.
-妳的“難吃”真的好搞笑 -不好笑
Why don't you make another kind of catchphrase?
妳何不創造新的招牌詞？
When the show's over, I don't know how to end it.
總覺得結束時，不知道該說什麼
A closing phrase?
結語嗎？
What would be good? Something like…
要說什麼好呢？比方說…
"Watch again tomorrow!"
“明天也要看喔”
At the end.
結尾時說
"Won't you watch again tomorrow? Yip!"
“明天也要看喔，嗷”
If Nobuta's going to say it, it should be cruder.
如果是野豬要說，應該要自然一點
"Won't you watch again tomorrow, morons?"
“明天也要看喔，蠢蛋”
"You idiot! It's supposed to be 'Yip!'"
“笨蛋，要說‘嗷’啦”
Okay, try that.
好，試試看吧
That could be funny.
那樣會很好笑
It is funny.
很搞笑
Put your hands like this.
手這樣放
"Won't you watch again tomorrow, morons?"
“明天也要看喔，蠢蛋”
"You idiot! It's supposed to be 'Yip!'"
“笨蛋，要說嗷啦”
"You idiot."
“笨蛋”
-Do it harder. -Hey! Don't touch her!
-再用力一點 -喂，別碰她
Okay. How about this?
好，這樣如何？
"Morons! You idiot!"
“蠢蛋，笨蛋”
-Chomp.
-大口吃
It's not an alligator!
又不是鱷魚
You want to fight, prick?
你討打啊，混蛋？
I'll bust your head, prick!
我要打爆你的頭，混帳
You want to fight?
想打架嗎？
Who do you think you are?
你以為你老幾啊？
Take that!
去死吧
You fucking prick! Fuck off!
你這混帳，滾開
Hey, you there! What the hell are you doing?
喂，你們在做什麼？ 你到底在做什麼？
-Tell your story later. -I'm not involved!
-等等再說 -不關我的事
If I get involved,
如果我多管閒事
nothing good will come of it.
不會有什麼好結果的
Who said you could get up?
誰說你可以起來的？
Shuji…
修二
Wow! The IT revolution of pasta!
天啊，義大利麵的資訊科技革命啊
That's amazing!
好厲害
-Shuji! -Yes?
-修二 -什麼？
-Lunch with Mariko? -Yes.
-你要跟真理子一起吃便當嗎？ -對啊
She's not coming for you today?
她今天不來接你嗎？
I thought I'd go to her first today.
今天我想先去找她
-What a nice guy! -Whoa!
-真帥氣 -天啊
See you.
再見，腳踏車
Hey, isn't Tani here today?
阿谷今天沒來嗎？
Yes. Tani is almost never absent.
對啊，阿谷幾乎從沒請假過
Yip yip.
嗷嗷
Where's Shuji?
修二呢？
Ouch, that hurts!
好痛喔
Shuji?
修二？
I know.
我知道了
Of course, he isn't there, dummy!
他當然不在那裡，笨蛋
So where's Shuji?
修二呢？
What's this?
這是什麼？
A bento lunch.
便當
Have it.
吃吧
Really? I can have it?
真的嗎？我可以吃嗎？
Yes. Go ahead.
對啊，請吃
Open! Whoa!
芝麻開門
Hey!
喂…
There's even a spoon and stuff!
還有湯匙和餐具啊
Mariko!
真理子
Thank you for this food!
我開動了
Go ahead.
請慢用
It's great!
太好吃了
This is like a dream.
好像在做夢一樣
Where's Shuji?
修二呢？
They're here! Attack time!
他們在這裡
Go in! Hurry!
進去，快點
Go ahead, Kotani!
去吧，小谷
Hurry up and attack!
快點突襲啊
Shuji isn't having lunch with Mariko.
修二今天沒有和真理子吃便當
Today, I'm doing a surprise check on Mariko Uehara's lunch.
今天我要突擊檢查上原真理子的便當
Who's eating with Mariko?
誰在和真理子一起吃飯？
Yip!
嗷
Kusano?
草野？
Astonishing! It's Kusano!
太驚人了，是草野
This is totally serious.
事態嚴重了
That was quite a lunch. I'm so full.
午餐真棒，好飽喔
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Was Mariko's bento lunch good?
真理子的便當好吃嗎？
The shrimp balls were great! Nice and thick!
蝦丸超好吃，又香又濃郁
The fried chicken took the longest time.
炸雞炸得最久
The fried chicken took the longest.
炸雞吃得最久
-I've heard that… -Ouch!
-我聽說… -好痛
Shrimp balls?
蝦丸啊？
You're such a big fat liar, Kiritani.
桐谷，你這個大騙子
You all right?
你沒事吧？
Yes.
沒事
Let me know if you need anything.
有什麼需要就跟我說
Excuse me!
借過
He got in a fight with guys from another school yesterday!
他昨天被別校的人打
-For real? -For real! He's all beat up!
-真的嗎？ -真的，他被揍得好慘
Seriously?
真的假的？
Tani!
阿谷
We just heard! Are you okay?
我們聽說了，你還好嗎？
-Yes. -That looks bad!
-還好 -看起來不妙
-You poor thing! -It's not as bad as it looks.
-真可憐 -沒有看起來那麼糟
Who did it?
是誰幹的？
I don't know them.
我不認識他們
You're kidding!
真的假的？
You okay?
你還好嗎？
Looks like you can't use your arm.
你的手不方便吧
If there's anything you need,
如果有任何需要
let me know.
就跟我說一聲
You knew it was me, right?
你知道是我，對吧？
What?
什麼？
You saw me when I was getting beat up, didn't you?
我被打的時候，你看到了吧？
What? What are you talking about?
什麼？你在說什麼？
You want to fight, prick?
你討打啊，混蛋？
I'll bust your head, prick!
我要打爆你的頭，混帳
Take that!
去死吧
You mean,
你是說…
that was you in that fight?
當時被打的人是你？
You're a jerk.
你是個混蛋
You ignored me, your own friend, getting beat up.
看到朋友被打，卻裝作沒看到
No, you're wrong. I really didn't notice.
不，你誤會了，我真的不知道是你
Unbelievable. You looked at me.
真不敢相信，你明明就看到我了
I mean it. I totally couldn't see anyone's face.
我是說真的，我沒有看到任何人的臉
You're such a smooth talker,
你真會狡辯啊
you're probably hoping you can convince me that I'm wrong.
你大概希望能騙過我吧
Now I know what kind of guy you really are.
我現在知道你的真面目了
Wait! Hold on!
等等，等一下
Did you hear that?
-你有聽到嗎？
I'm telling the truth!
我說的是實話
Believe me!
相信我
Everyone says that.
大家都這麼說
"Please, believe me."
“請相信我”
-You mean Shuji saw but didn't help? -Yes.
-你是說修二看到了，卻沒幫忙？ -是啊
That's what it sounds like.
聽起來是這樣
-I won't stand for that. -Yes.
不可原諒
Wouldn't you call the police?
要是妳的話，應該會報警吧？
That's for sure. I'd call them or a passerby.
那當然，我會報警或是找路人幫忙
Shuji!
修二
Hey!
喂
Did you really ignore Tani?
你真的對阿谷見死不救嗎？
Say something!
說話啊
Let's go home together.
我們一起回家吧
Wiggle wiggle!
搖啊搖
Shuji!
修二
I really can't believe Shuji would do that.
真不敢相信修二會做這種事
Morning.
早安
Kiritani is actually way different than he always seemed.
看不出來桐谷竟然是那種人
From now on,
從現在開始
don't you guys ever come up and talk to me.
你們別再來找我說話
Okay?
好嗎？
Bye.
再見
Why?
為什麼？
I don't want people to think you guys are like me,
我不希望別人認為你們跟我一樣
especially Nobuta. You've gained popularity recently.
尤其是野豬，妳最近變得受歡迎了
Don't you dare talk to me.
千萬別跟我說話
Isn't it true that you couldn't tell that it was Tani getting beat up?
你真的不知道 被揍的那個人是阿谷嗎？
Then don't you think you should tell everyone that?
你不覺得應該澄清這件事嗎？
There's no point in telling them.
現在說什麼都沒用了
Right now, it will just sound like an excuse.
聽起來只會像藉口
But if you don't do anything…
但如果你什麼都不做…
You see,
現在…
my words don't carry any weight now.
我說什麼都無所謂了
Nobody believes…
不會有人相信
anything I say now.
我說的任何一個字
This is what it means…
不被信任
when nobody believes you.
就是這樣的感覺吧
Aoi…
蒼井
Why were you photographing me?
妳為什麼要拍我？
I was photographing Shuji Kiritani taking out his anger on pigeons.
我剛剛在拍桐谷修二遷怒鴿子的照片
You shouldn't harm animals.
你不能傷害動物
I'm making a record of your growth.
我在製作你的成長紀錄
A record?
紀錄？
You mean you've photographed other things?
所以妳還拍了其他東西？
Of course.
當然
Ever since the time you proclaimed you would be a producer for Nobuta.
自從你宣布要改造野豬開始
I've got lots of photos.
我拍了很多照片
I'll show you sometime.
改天讓你看看
How did you know that?
妳怎麼知道那件事的？
Who are you?
妳是誰？
Kotani's friend?
小谷的朋友？
Kotani…
小谷…
DIE
（去死）
You mean…
難道…
all that harassment…
所有的惡作劇
Yes. That's right.
對，沒錯
I did all that.
都是我做的
This is what I was thinking of doing next.
接下來我打算公開這個
Poor Kusano will be shocked.
可憐的草野一定會很震驚
Are you surprised?
你很驚訝嗎？
Why?
為什麼？
"Why?"
“為什麼？”
Are you asking why I'm doing this?
你問我為什麼要這麼做嗎？
I think it's probably for the same reason you're producing for Kotani.
或許跟你改造小谷的理由一樣吧
You can hide in the shadows and act like you're not involved at all.
你可以躲在暗處 假裝什麼事都沒發生
Being able to change someone through your own actions
用自己的行動去改變別人
sure is fun, isn't it?
真的很有趣，對吧？
Right?
對吧？
Bye.
再見
See you tomorrow.
明天見
These little pigs bring good luck.
這些小豬會帶來好運
-They're talismans. -Talismans?
這是護身符
Talismans?
護身符？
I'm home.
我回來了
-Welcome home. -These are yours, Shuji.
-你回來啦 -哥，這是你的
What are these?
這些是什麼？
Mom sent them.
是媽寄來的
They're souvenirs from Chile. Three-legged pig talismans.
是智利的伴手禮，三腳豬護身符
Remember how she asked you on the phone the other day
她前幾天在電話上問過你
how many friends you have?
你有幾個朋友，記得嗎？
-Oh, yeah. -You've got two friends, right?
-沒錯 -你有兩個朋友吧？
So including you, that's three.
加上你就有三個人
How do you use these?
這個有什麼用？
It looks like they're for friendship.
好像可以守護友情
You probably give them to friends as a symbol of your friendship.
應該是把它送給朋友 當作友情的象徵
A symbol of friendship…
友情的象徵
If you both have one,
如果彼此都有這個
then they probably bring lifelong, unflagging friendship.
他們的友誼可能一輩子不變
How long do they work?
它的功效有多長？
Forever, of course.
當然是永遠啊
-Forever? -Yes.
-永遠？ -對
Then maybe I won't give them out.
那我或許不該送出去
-You don't want it to be forever? -Yes.
-你不希望友情永遠不變？ -對啊
Who's the next "Attack" victim?
誰是下一個“突襲”的受害者？
Good morning.
早安
Let's go.
走吧
Morning. Good morning, everyone.
早安，大家早安
-Good morning. -Morning.
-早安
Morning.
早安
You want to get monjayaki again?
妳又想吃文字燒嗎？
-Yes. -Do you know about strawberry milk?
-對 -妳知道草莓牛奶口味嗎？
-No. -It's like a dessert. It's sweet and good.
-不知道 -那跟甜點一樣，甜甜的很好吃
And let's go to a place only for girls again.
我們去只有女生的餐廳吃飯吧
What is it? Why do you want to talk to me?
怎麼了？你為什麼要叫我來？
How can I
我要怎麼做
get you to stop?
妳才願意停止？
Stop what?
停止什麼？
This.
這個
You just want me to stop?
你要我停手？
I want you to stop seeing Kotani and never talk to her again.
我要妳別再跟小谷見面 也別再跟她說話
I knew it.
我就知道
That's what it is.
果然沒錯
Your weakness is Kotani and Kusano, isn't it?
你的弱點是小谷和草野吧？
For Kotani,
對小谷來說
you're her first friend.
妳是她的第一個朋友
So if she found out the truth…
如果她發現真相…
I see why you're worried.
難怪你會這麼擔心
She's been hurt badly ever since she was a kid.
她從小就受到很嚴重的傷害
So why do you have to hurt her more than she already is?
為什麼妳還要繼續傷害她？
Don't tell her.
千萬別告訴她
Maybe I will.
不好說
I'm begging you. Please don't tell her.
我求妳了，拜託別告訴她
Don't worry. I won't tell her yet.
別擔心，我還不會告訴她
I'm waiting until we're closer friends.
我要等到我們成為 更親密的朋友再跟她說
I plan on
我打算…
plunging Kotani into such deep despair that she would want to kill herself.
讓小谷陷入絕望，讓她想自殺
What?
什麼？
What's your damn problem?
妳有什麼毛病？
No! Stop! Let go of me!
住手，放開我
No! Stop! Let go!
不要，快放手
Don't you do that, Shuji!
別這樣，修二
Bad hand! Bad! Bad!
壞手手，不乖…
Kiritani tried to…
桐谷想…
Kiritani said…
桐谷說…
that I was the one who wrecked the haunted house.
他說鬼屋是我破壞的
But I didn't do anything!
但我什麼都沒做啊
It's wrong to raise your fist against a woman, you know. Pow!
對女人動手是不對的喔
But knowing you, I'm sure you had a good reason.
但以我對你的了解 你一定有個好理由
Do you…
你…
believe me?
相信我嗎？
You bet! I believe you.
我當然相信你啊
No matter what?
無論如何都相信？
No matter what.
無論如何都相信
I promise.
我保證
No.
不用
Don't promise.
不用保證
How come?
為什麼？
Well…
不過…
If you believe me…
如果你相信我
If you still believe
如果你還相信…
what I say…
我說的話
Then I've got something to tell you.
那我有件事要告訴你
Tell me now.
現在就說吧
Well, you see…
那個…
My head's so mixed up right now.
我現在腦子一片混亂
Can you wait until I've figured things out?
能等我釐清頭緒再跟你說嗎？
I don't really get it.
我不太懂是怎麼回事
But all right.
但我知道了
We're always best friends!
我們永遠都是好朋友
Shuji!
修二
Is it true that Aoi wrecked the haunted house?
真的是蒼井破壞鬼屋的嗎？
Who said that?
誰說的？
Aoi said you said that to her.
蒼井說是你說的
I said that?
我說的？
I didn't say that.
我沒那麼說
There's no way Aoi would do that.
蒼井不可能做那種事
I mean, she's your friend.
她是妳的朋友
Right?
對吧？
Kotani.
小谷
Yes! Akira is happy!
好耶，彰開心
What?
什麼？
Akira is shocked!
彰心碎滿地
Isn't there any other outfit?
沒有別的服裝嗎？
What's wrong with being vampires?
當吸血鬼又有什麼關係？
Wait!
等等
Who's there?
是誰在那裡？
You saw us, didn't you?
妳看到我們了吧？
So could you tell how I did it?
妳有識破我的手法嗎？
No, it's all right.
沒有
We can change now, right?
我們可以換裝了吧？
Let's practice a little more.
再多練習一下
Can't I do it in my regular clothes?
不能穿便服練嗎？
Well…
那個…
What is this?
你們為什麼要準備這表演？
Entertainment for the end-of-year party.
尾牙餐會的餘興節目
You know, I wonder if
我在想…
vampires really do exist.
吸血鬼是不是真的存在
I don't think they do.
應該不存在吧
I guess they don't.
可能吧
But, you know,
不過
if even one person on Earth believes in them,
只要這世界上有一個人相信
I get the feeling they exist.
我就能感覺到他們的存在
We don't believe things because they're true.
我們不會因為是真的才相信
Things are true because we believe them.
是因為我們相信了，才會是真的
Understand?
明白嗎？
The day everyone stops believing,
等到大家都不再相信的那天
that's probably the day
或許就是…
that vampires disappear from existence.
吸血鬼從世上消失的那天
Which hand?
哪隻手？
What?
什麼？
It looks like it is in your right hand.
應該是在妳的右手吧
Then which one is it in?
所以是哪隻手？
Choose the one you believe it is.
選擇妳認為正確的答案
Nobody knows what the real truth is.
沒有人知道真相是什麼
Then your only choice is the one you want to believe in, right?
所以妳只能相信自己想相信的
The one I want to believe…
自己想相信的…
You're right!
妳答對了
Yip yip!
嗷嗷
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
What is it?
發生什麼事了？
I saw something that
我看到一件…
I didn't want to see.
我不想看到的事
And?
然後呢？
I want to act like I never saw it.
我想假裝沒看到
I see.
這樣啊
But that's not possible,
但那是不可能的
is it?
對吧？
Yes, it is.
沒錯
No way! Ouch!
不會吧？好痛
So this makes me unsee it?
這麼做能讓我忘記嗎？
Yes.
是啊
Our family has always put things
我們家族總是
we didn't want to see in here and sealed them away.
把不想看到的東西藏起來
That's how we act like it didn't happen.
我們會假裝什麼都沒發生
I'll give you some of this fermenting miso.
我給你一些發酵味噌
So put whatever you like in here.
你想放什麼進去都可以
When you pull it out in a few decades,
幾十年後拿出來
I'm sure you'll laugh about it.
我敢說你一定會一笑置之的
There!
塞進去
Will I really laugh?
我真的會笑出來嗎？
You bet you'll laugh.
你一定會笑出來的
That stinks.
好臭
"Even if you're devastated,
“就算是遍體鱗傷
it doesn't mean life is over."
人生也不會就此結束”
Just like I was told,
正如他所說的
life didn't feel like it was going to end.
人生並沒有要結束的感覺
Good morning.
早安
Even so,
就算是這樣
I still have to continue living.
我還是得活下去
You're still eating this yucky stuff?
你還在吃這種難吃的東西？
Like the Goyokudo guy said,
就像豪翼堂老闆說的
as long as you have life, there will be miserable days.
“只要活著，就會有悲慘的日子
However, there will also be awesome days.
但是，也會有很棒的日子”
The way things are now,
照現在的情況看來
will I ever really have awesome days again?
我還能有很棒的日子嗎？
If you believe,
只要你相信
any problem can be solved.
任何問題都能解決
Believe with me.
跟我一起相信吧
Nobuta power charge!
野豬能量，注入
Charge!
注入
Shuji.
修二
Let's go home together.
我們一起回家吧
Okay.
好
Let's go home.
我們回家吧
Ready, go!
一、二
-Nobuta power charge!
-野豬能量，注入
Yip!
嗷
I don't care if nobody believes me.
我不在乎是否有人相信我
I simply want these guys to believe in me.
我只希望這兩個傢伙相信我
AKIRA KUSANO
（草野彰）
Now and forever.
永遠相信我
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
字幕翻譯：黃雅婷